A Guide to the Papers of Ambrose Bierce, 1842-1914
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- A Lost Chapter in the Career of Ambrose Bierce, the Black Hills Correspondence
  - Volume I
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 AUG 7, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 48
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 AUG 8, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 10 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 49-58
      - "Copy of Resolutions passed at a meeting of the Directors of the Black Hills Placer Mining Cy." 1880 AUG 11, ADS. 1 p. (Box 6)
      - "Extracts from the Minutes of a Meeting of the Executive Committee of the Black Hills Placer Mining Co." 1880 AUG 9, ADS. 1 p. (Box 6)
    - [A. G. Bierce], Rockerville, D.T., to "My Dear Shelb" [Shelburne Blake Eaton] 1880 AUG 16, AL. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 5 p. [incomplete]. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 59-63
    - Omitted in numbering (Box 6)
      p. 64
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 AUG 19, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 4 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 65-68
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Shelb" [Shelburne Blake Eaton] 1880 SEP 2, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 14 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 69-82
    - contains a faint image of p.82 (Box 6)
      p. 83
    - "To show the animus of this thing... " (signed "B") n.d., ANS [postscript]. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 84
    - Statement of account, A. G. Bierce, Genl Agt., Black Hills Placer Mining Co. [1880] JUL-SEP, AD. 2 p. (Box 6)
      p. 84.a
    - Statement of account, [Black Hills Placer Mining Co.] [1880] SEP, AD. 1 p. (Box 6)
      p. 84.b
    - H. A. Iddings, Rockerville, Dakota, to Marcus Walker, Treas[urer], Black Hills Placer Mining Co. 1880 SEP 3, ALS. (marked "copy"). 2 p. (Box 6)
      p. 84.c
    - A. G. B[ierce], allegation of inaccuracies in three versions of "statement of liabilities furnished by Mr. Iddings." 1880 SEP 3, ADS. 1 p. (Box 6)
      p. 84.d
      - "Indebtedness of I. M. West" and account of I. M. West with Black Hills Placer Mining Co. 1880 APR-AUG, AD. 6 p. w/ dkt. (Box 6)
        - attached
    - Statements of indebtedness of I. M. West (marked "copy"). [1880] SEP, AD. 16 p. (Box 6)
      p. 84.e
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to "My Dear Shelb" [Shelburne Blake Eaton] 1880 SEP 4, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 6 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 85-90
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis 1880 SEP 4, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 5 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 91-95
  - Volume II
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 5, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 96-98
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis 1880 SEP 5, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 5 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 99-103
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 6, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 104-106
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 9, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil, "private" in ink). 5 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 107-111.
      p. 112 omitted in numbering
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 11, ALS. (marked "confidential" in ink). 7 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 113-120.
      p. 115 omitted in numbering
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to Mr. Rigby 1880 SEP 11, ALS. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 121
    - [A. J. Chamlee], Rockerville, D.T., to Major A. G. Bierce. 1880 SEP 13, ALS. 1 p. (Box 6)
      p. 121.a
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 13, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 4 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 122-124
    - A. G. Bierce, Gen.Agt., Rockerville, D.T., to Major S. B. Eaton. 1880 SEP 14, ALS. 4 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 125-128
    - A. G. Bierce, Gen.Agt., Rockerville, D.T., to Major S. B. Eaton. 1880 SEP 14, ALS. 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 129-131
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis 1880 SEP 14, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil, "private" in ink). 5 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 132-135
    - A. G. Bierce to "My Dear Shelb" [Shelburne Blake Eaton] 1880 SEP 15, ALS. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 136
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 15, ALS. (marked "private" in ink). 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 137-139
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 15, ALS. (marked "private" in ink). 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 140-141
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 1, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 142-143
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to "Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 17, ALS. (marked "confidential" in ink). 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 144-145
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 17, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 146-147
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 SEP 18, ALS. 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 148-150
    - Omitted in numbering (Box 6)
      p. 151-157
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 23, ALS. (marked "personal" in ink). 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      P. 158-159
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 23, ALS. (marked "personal" in ink). 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 160-161
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Gen. Alex[ander] Shaler 1880 SEP 23, ALS. (marked "private / personal" in ink). 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 162-164
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to Major S. B. Eaton. 1880 SEP 24, ALS. 9 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 165-173
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to Major S. B. Eaton, submitting his resignation. 1880 SEP 24, ALS. 1 p. (Box 6)
      p. 173.a
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to Major S. B. Eaton, submitting his resignation. 1880 SEP 24, ALS. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 174
    - [H.] Kaufman, San Francisco, to "My dear Bierce." 1880 SEP 24, ALS. 4 p. (Box 6)
      p. 174.a
    - "Shelb" [Shelburne Blake Eaton], Law Office of Chamberlaine, Carter & Eaton, 346 Broadway, New York, to [Ambrose Bierce]. 1880 SEP 27, ALS. 2 p. (Box 6)
      p. 174.b
    - Omitted in numbering (Box 6)
      p. 175-185
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton," (marked "personal" in pencil). 1880 SEP 27, ALS. 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p.186-188
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 SEP 30, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 7 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 189-195
    - "Mining Claims Located under Instructions of Genl. Alex[ander] Shaler" (Listed by class: A, B, C, D) [1880], AD. 11 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 196-206
    - Omitted in numbering: p. 207 is an indecipherable copy (Box 6)
      p. 204
    - "Men Unpaid on July Rolls" (lists for September and August follow) [1880], AD. 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 208-211
    - Contains indecipherable copy (Box 6)
      p. 210
    - "Deductions Made from Men's Pay - A/C Geo[rge] Macer" (lists for deductions by Higly & Co., L. E. Parish, and E.Barthall follow) [1880], AD. 4 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 212-215
    - Omitted in numbering (Box 6)
      p. 216
    - "Payments to Laborers on A/C A. I. Hartford" [1880], AD. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 217
  - Volume III
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton," (marked "personal" in pencil). 1880 OCT 5, ALS. 5 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 218-222
    - Statement of account, W. H. Beedle, in account with Black Hills Placer Mining Co. [1880] JUL-OCT, AD. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 223
    - Statement of account, Gates & Goughnour, in account with Black Hills Placer Mining Co. [1880] JUL-AUG, AD. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 224
    - Statement of account, Jeff McDermott, in account with Black Hills Placer Mining Co. [1880] APR-MAY, AD. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 225
    - "List of Papers in the Office of Black Hills Placer Mining Co." [in Bierce's handwriting] [1880], AD. 9 p. w/dkt. (Box 7)
      p. 225.a
    - "List of Papers in the Office of Black Hills Placer Mining Co." [in Bierce's handwriting] [1880], AD. 7 p. letterpress copy of pages 1-7 of preceding item (continued on page 281) (Box 7)
      p. 226-232
    - "Trestles in Flume" no date, AD. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 233
    - "List of Water Rights and Mining Claims of the Black Hills Placer Mining Co." [in Bierce's handwriting] [1880], AD. 3 p. w/dkt. (Box 7)
      p. 233.a
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 OCT 7, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 234-236
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton," 1880 OCT 7, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 7 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 237-244
    - Omitted in numbering (Box 7)
      p. 238
    - "List of Water Rights and Mining Claims of the Black Hills Placer Mining Co." [in Bierce's handwriting] [1880], AD. 3 p. letterpress copy of item on page 233.a (Box 7)
      p. 245-247
      ("probably imperfect" and [see list on] "page 196" written in pencil)
    - A. G. Bierce, General Agent, Rockerville, to Mr. [D.] McLaughlin 1880 OCT 8, ALS. 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 248-250
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 OCT, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 251-252
    - Omitted in numbering (Box 7)
      p. 253
    - "List of Deductions Unpaid on October Rolls" [1880], AD. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 254
      (Several initial letters written in pencil)
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 OCT 10, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 6 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 255-260
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to "My Dear Eaton" 1880 OCT 11, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil). 7 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 261-267
    - Omitted in numbering (Box 7)
      p. 268-270
    - "Actions Pending in the Courts" 1880 OCT 13, AD. 7 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 271-277
      (in Bierce's handwriting)
    - "Trial Balance / Black Hills Placer Mining Co." 1880 OCT 14, AD. 1 p. w/dkt. (Box 7)
      p. 277.a
    - A. G. Bierce to Messrs. McLaughlin & Steele. 1880 OCT 15, ALS. 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 278-279
    - A. G. Bierce to B. G. Caulfield. 1880 OCT 15, ALS. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 280
    - "List of Papers in the Office of Black Hills Placer Mining Co." [1880], AD. [in Bierce's handwriting.] 2 p. letterpress copy of pages 8-9 of item on p. 225.a. (continued from page 232) (Box 7)
      p. 281-282
    - A. G. Bierce, Gen. Agent., Black Hills Placer Mining Company, Rockerville, D.T., to E. S. Kaufman. 1880 OCT 15, ALS. 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 283-284
    - A. G. Bierce, Gen. Agent., Black Hills Placer Mining Company, Rockerville, D.T., to Boone May. 1880 OCT 15, ALS. 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 285-286
    - Statement of account, A. G. Bierce, Gen. Agt., with Black Hills Placer Mining Co. 1880 OCT 16, AD. 1 p. (Box 7)
      p. 286.a
    - A G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to Gen. Alexander Shaler, president. 1880 OCT 16, AL. 2 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 287-288
    - Is a faint letterpress copy of an unidentified item (Box 7)
      p. 289
    - "List of Employees / Black Hills Placer Mining Co." no date, AM. (in Bierce's handwriting.) 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 290
    - "Index to Letter Book" ("Official" inserted in pencil) no date, AM. (in Bierce's handwriting.) 4 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      p. 291-294
    - "Indebtedness Accrued since Sept. 6th 1880" 1880 OCT 16, AD. (In Bierce's handwriting.) 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 7)
      This item is bound between pages 287 and 288.
      p. 295
    - Receipts for vouchers and cash received from A. G. Bierce for E. S. Kaufman, signed by Marcus Walker, Genl Manager. 1880 OCT. 27, ADS. 2 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.a
    - Statement of account, A. G. Bierce, with Black Hills Placer Min'g Comp'y. 1880 NOV 1, AD. 1 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.b
    - Statement of account, in settlement, The Black Hills Placer M. Co. to A. G. Bierce. 1880 NOV 17, AD. 1 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.c
    - "Ambrose Bierce's Black Hills Litigation, 1881-1886", title page (Box 7)
      p. 295.d
    - A. G. Bierce, Auburn, Cal'a, to [John H.] Boalt. 1885 APR 16, ALS. 4 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.e
    - "Enclosures with the Bierce letter / Exhibits A-L", title page (Box 7)
      p. 295.f
    - McLaughlin & Steele, Attorneys-at-Law, Deadwood, Dakota, to Ambrose G. Bierce, Oakland, CA. 1881 SEP 8, AL. 6 p. (marked "Exhibit A" in pencil) (Box 7)
      p. 295.g
    - Deposition of Ambrose Bierce (answers; the questions are not included) [1881 SEP], AD. 14 p. (marked "Exhibit B" in pencil) (Box 7)
      p. 295.h
    - Transcript of cross examination of Ambrose Bierce, in Ambrose Bierce v. The First National Bank, Deadwood, First Judicial District, District Court of Lawrence County, D.T. No Date, AD. 5 p. (marked "Exhibit C" in pencil) (Box 7)
      p. 295.i
    - Power of Attorney, Ambrose G. Bierce to William R. Steele. No Date, AD. 1 p. (marked "not executed / A.G.B") (Box 7)
      p. 295.j
    - McLaughlin & Steele, Attorneys-at-Law, Deadwood, Dakota, to Ambrose G. Bierce, San Francisco, CA. 1883 NOV 20, AL. 2 p. (marked "Exhibit D" in pencil) (Box 7)
      p. 295.k
    - Deposition of Ambrose Bierce [1881], AD. (questions and answers; the answers are written in purple ink) 2 p. (marked "Exhibit E" in pencil) (Box 7)
      p. 295.l
    - McLaughlin & Steele, Attorneys-at-Law, Deadwood, Dakota, to Ambrose G. Bierce, Nicasio, CA. 1883 DEC 26, AL. 4 p. (marked "Exhibit F" in pencil) (Box 7)
      p. 295.m
    - M. McLaughlin, Deadwood, Dakota, to Ambrose G. Bierce, Nicasio, CA. 1883 DEC 31, ALS. 2 p. (marked "Exhibit G" in pencil) (Box 7)
      p. 295.n
    - Assignment of Rights to [Mining] Claim [in contest], [Ambrose G. Bierce] to McLaughlin & Steele, Attorneys of Deadwood, Dakota Territory, for the use of The Black Hills Placer Mining Company. 1884 JAN __, AD. 1 p. (marked in pencil: "copy," "Exhibit H," "(signed) A G Bierce," and "Executed about May 8 1884") (Box 7)
      p. 295.o
    - McLaughlin & Steele, Attorneys-at-Law, Deadwood, Dakota, to Ambrose G. Bierce, Auburn, Placer Co., Cal. 1884 JAN 26, AL. 2 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.p
    - Ambrose G. Bierce, Auburn, Placer Co., Cala.,to Messrs. McLaughlin & Steele. 1 p. w/dkt. (marked "copy" in ink and "Exhibit J" in pencil) 1884 MAY 8, ALS (Box 7)
      p. 295.q
    - McLaughlin & Steele, Attorneys-at-Law, Deadwood, Dakota, to Ambrose G. Bierce, Auburn, Cal. 1885 FEB 12, AL. 4 p. (marked "Exhibit K" in pencil) (Box 7)
      p. 295.r
    - Assignment of Rights to [Mining] Claim [in settlement for services rendered], The Black Hills Placer Mining Company, New York, NY, to Daniel McLaughlin and William R. Steele, Attorneys-in-Law, Deadwood, Dakota Territory, with notarial attestation. 1884 JAN 14, AD. 5 p. w/dkt. (marked "Exhibit L" in pencil) (Box 7)
      p. 295.s
    - "Boalt's reply to Bierce and ensuing correspondence in re the Black Hills Litigation", title page (Box 7)
      p. 295.t
    - John H. Boalt, San Francisco [CA], to "My Dear Bierce" 1885 APR 20, ALS. 6 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.u
    - John H. Boalt, San Francisco [CA], to "My Dear Bierce" 1885 APR 24, ALS. 9 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.v
    - John H. Boalt, San Francisco [CA], to the Clerk of the District Court, Deadwood, Dakota. 1885 APR 26, ALS. 1 p. (marked "copy" in ink) (Box 7)
      p. 295.w
    - John H. Boalt, San Francisco [CA], to "My Dear Bierce" 1885 MAY 1, ALS. 1 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.x
    - A.R.Z. Dawson, Clerk of the District Court, Deadwood, Dak., to John H. Boalt, San Francisco, Cal. 1885 MAY 4, ALS. 1 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.y
    - John H. Boalt, San Francisco [CA], to "My Dear Bierce" 1885 MAY 14, ALS. 1 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.z
    - A.R.Z. Dawson, Clerk of the District Court, Deadwood, Dak., to A. G. Bierce, San Francisco, Cal. 1885 AUG 8, ALS. 2 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.aa
    - A.R.Z. Dawson, Clerk of the District Court, Deadwood, Dak., to A. G. Bierce. 1886 JAN 28, ALS. 1 p. (Box 7)
      p. 295.bb
      - Stock Certificate, 150 shares, The Sherwood Mines Company to Ambrose Bierce, Washington, DC. 1908 MAY 19, 2 p. (marginal notations: "void" and "for Helen Bierce Isgrigg" (Box 7)
        - inserted inside of back cover
- Scrapbook Series
  - Volume 1, Leather-bound blank book (20.5*17.5 cm)
    Containing reviews of Bierce's books, clipped from a variety of newspapers. Generally, the sources of the clippings were identified in ink at the conclusion of each article, but the dates of publication were not. Pagination added: 1-63, p. 44-46 blank. [MSS # 5992-a]
    - Tales of Soldiers and Civilians (and) in the midst of Life (Box 7)
      p. 1-43
    - Black Beetles in Amber (Box 7)
      p. 47-63
  - Volume 2, Leather-bound blank book (20.5* 17.5 cm)
    Containing reviews of Bierce's books, clipped from a variety of newspapers. Generally, the sources of the clippings were identified in ink at the conclusion of each article, but the dates of publication were not. Pagination added: 6-55, p. 26 blank. [MSS # 5992-a]
    - Black Beetles in Amber (Box 7)
      p. 1-4
    - Tales of Soldiers and Civilians (and) in teh midist of Life (Box 7)
      p. 5-55
  - Volume 3, Leather-bound blank book (20.5 * 17.5 cm)
    Containing reviews of Bierce's books, clipped from a variety of newspapers. Generally, the sources of the clippings were identified in ink at the conclusion of each article, but the dates of publication were not. Pagination added: 1-46, p. 17-18, 26 blank. [MSS #5992-a]
    - Can Such Things Be? (Box 7)
      p. 1-15
    - The Monk and the Hangman's Daughter (Box 7)
      p. 19-25
    - Fantastic Fables (Box 7)
      p. 27-45
  - Volume 4, Gray cloth-bound blank book (24 * 19 cm)
    Embossed "Scrap Book" in gold on the cover. Generally, the sources of the clippings were identified in ink at the conclusion of each article, but the dates of publication were not. Pagination added: 1-19 [MSS # 5992-a]
    - The News Letter as it Was (Box 8)
      p. 1-9
      Clippings from various sources re: San Francisco "News Letter"
    - English Opinions of a Worthless Book (Box 8)
      p. 10-19
      Revies of Bierce's book: The Fiend's Delight by Dod Grile, (pseud.)
  - Volume 5, Bound blank book (30 * 25.5 cm) with marbled-paper covers; spine missing. (Box 8)
    Contains early artiles by Bierce, approximately 1884-1888, but the clippings are not in strict chronological sequence. Teh date and place of publcaiton of some of the articles was noted by Bierce in ink or pencil. Pagination added: 13-137; p. 36-136 blank
  - Volume 6, Brown cloth-bound blank book (30 * 23 cm), inscribed by Bierce, "For Helen Bierce," inside the front cover in pencil. (Box 8)
    Contains various articles and columns by Bierce, ca. 1893-1902, but the clippings are not in chronological sequence, and many lack dates.
    Many of the clippings were folded to fit within the size of book and some items are obscured by others.
    Pagination added: 1-61 [MSS # 5992-a]
  - Volume 7, Black cloth-bound blank book (34.5 * 29 com), with decorative embossing on covers and embossed "Scrap Album" in gold on front cover. (Box No box)
    Inscribed in ink by Bierce inside front cover: "Book 1, Jan. 1893 - Dec. 1894."
    Contains Ambrose Bierce's column, "Prattle."
    The clippings appear to be arranged in strict chronological order.
    Pagination added: 1-57 [MSS # 5992-a]
  - Volume 8, Gray cloth-bound blank book (27.5 * 21 cm), with decorative embossing on covers an spine in black and embossed "Scrap Book" in black on spine. (Box 8)
    Inscribed in ink by Bierce inside front cover: "Book 2, Jan 1895 - Nov. 1895."
    The clippings appear to be arranged in strict chronological order. Pagination added: 1-64 [MSS # 5992-a]
  - Volume 9, Black cloth-bound blank book (28 *21 cm), with red mock-leather corner trim and spines. Embossed "Scrap Book" in gold on covers; the spine is detached. Inscribed in ink by Bierce inside front cover: "Book III, 1895-96-97-98." (Box 9)
    Contains titled columns by Ambrose Bierce, beginning with "Prattle," and including other of his columns published in later years, although many of the clippings omit the column title. The clippings appear to be in fairly good chronological order, although some items lack dates. Pagination added: 1-123 [MSS # 5992-a]
  - Volume 10, Black cloth-bound blank book (28 * 21 cm), with red mock-leather conrner trim and spines. Embossed "Scrap Book" in gold on covers; the spine is detached. (Box 9)
    Vol. 10 Covers the period 1899 Jan. 1 - 1900 Oct. 12. Contains titled columns by Ambrose Bierce, beginning with "Prattle," and including other of his columns published in later years, although many of the clippings omit the column title. The clippings appear to be in fairly good chronological order, although some items lack dates. Pagination added: 1-120 [MSS # 5992-a]
  - Volume 11, Black cloth-bound blank book (28 * 21 cm), with red mock-leather conrner trim and spines. Embossed "Scrap Book" in gold on covers; the spine is detached. (Box 10)
    Vol. 11 covers the period 1900 Oct. 14-1903 May 18. Contains titled columns by Ambrose Bierce, beginning with "Prattle," and including other of his columns published in later years, although many of the clippings omit the column title. The clippings appear to be in fairly good chronological order, although some items lack dates. Pagination added: 1-30, 30A, 30B, 31 -40, 40A, 40B, 41-116
    To correct an obvious error, two detached leaves containing items dating from 1901 found in the back of vol. 10 were replaced in vol. 11 by date and repaginated as p. 36-A/36-B and 40-A/40-B.
    In addition to Bierce's columns, vol. 11 includeds Bierce's reviews of others' books: [MSS # 5992-a]
    - "Four new books and what I think of them" (Box 10)
      p.33
      - Backsheesh-A Woman's Wanderings by Mrs. William Beckman
      - A Furnace of Earth by Hallie Erminie Rives
      - The Lion at the Well by Lionel Josephare
      - Taliesin a Masque by Richard Hovey
    - "Three new books and what I think of them (Box 10)
      p.34/35
      - Melodies-Lyre Touches From the Hudson by William Benignus
      - The Goldsmith of Nome by Sam C. Dunham
      - Jacinta and Other Verses by Howard V. Sutherland
  - Volume 12, Black cloth-bound blank book (36 * 25 cm.), Embossed on the cover, "Scrap Book" in gold above a decorative device. Although some clippings are annotated in Bierce's hand, this volume was compiled posthumously. (Box 10)
    Pagination added: 1-131, 131A, 131B, 132-145. Most of the items lack dates, and those that are dated are not in chronological order. Of the items that are dated, the earliest date noted is 1888 Feb 19 (p.65) and the latest is 1904 Nov 29 (p.115). Although many items lack mastheads, most appear to be Bierce's titled columns: [MSS # 5992-a]
    - "Ambrose Bierce Says" (Box 10)
      p.133
    - "Prattle" (Box 10)
      p. 102-132
    - "The Passing Show"
      p. 1-101, 133-145
  - Volume 13, Black cloth-bound blank book (36 * 25 cm.), embossed on the cover, "Scrap Book" in gold above a decorative device. Although some clippings are annotated in Bierce's hand, this volume was compiled posthumously. (Box 11)
    Pagination added: 1-145.
    Most items lack dates, and those that are dated are not in chronological order. OF the dated items, the earliest is 1888 Jan 22 (p.93); the latest is 1906 Jun _(p.18).